Guide to the John P. Marquand Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Stephen Birmingham Papers, 1930-73; Series III; 2.52; (7 boxes)
  - RESEARCH MATERIAL
    - Research Files
      - Marquand, John P.
        - Death, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1000)
        - Genealogy, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1001)
        - Lifestyle, 1940-60 (Box 45, Folder 1002)
        - Trial, 1949 (Box 45, Folder 1003)
        - Works
          - Life at Happy Knoll, 1955-59, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1004)
          - Melville Goodwin, USA (Film, 1955), 1951-55, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1005)
          - Sincerely, Willis Wayde, 1952-55 (Box 45, Folder 1006)
          - Stopover Tokyo, 1955-57, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1007)
          - Thirty Years, 1953-54 (Box 45, Folder 1008)
          - Wickford Point (Film, 1955), 1951-55 (Box 45, Folder 1009)
          - Women and Thomas Harrow, 1957-58 (Box 45, Folder 1010)
      - Marquand, John P., Jr.
        See: Box 44, folders 994 and 996; Box 49, folders 1084 and 1086
      - Mayes, Herbert R., 1970 (Box 45, Folder 1011)
        See also: Box 45, folders 998 and 1011
      - Merck, George W.
        Related Materials
      - Newberry, Cammann
        See: Box 44, folder 995; Box 45, folder 1007
      - Potter, Brooks
        See: Box 44, folders 975-76, and 994-96; Box 45, folder 1002; Box 49, folders 1085-87
      - Potter, H. C.
        See: Box 45, folder 1005
      - Reed, John
      - Rose, Stuart
        See: Box 45, folders 1007 and 1010
      - Salmen, Stanley
        See: Box 44, folder 975; Box 45, folders 1005-06 and 1008
      - Saunders, Dorothy
      - Schneider, Anne Kaufman
        See: Box 45, folder 999; Box 48, folder 1073a; Box 49, folders 1073d and 1088
      - Sedgwick, R. Minturn
        See: Box 44, folder 994; Box 49, folders 1073c-d and 1085
      - Sions, Harry
        See: Box 44, folders 975, 990, 994-95, and 997; Box 45, folder 999; Box 49, folders 1073b and 1804-87
      - Stark, Ray
        See: Box 44, folder 990; Box 45, folder 1005
      - Stevens, George
      - Streeter, Ed, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1012)
        See also: Box 45, folder 998; Box 49, folder 1073c
      - Thornhill, Arthur H.
        See: Box 44, folders 989, 991, 993-97; Box 45, folder 1010; Box 49, folders 1085-7
      - Vidor, King
      - Welch, Christina ("Tina") Marquand
        See: Box 44, folders 977, 991, and 995; Box 45, folder 1002; Box 49, folder 1073d
      - White, William
        See: Box 44, folder 997; Box 49, folder 1087
      - Williams, Alexander W.
        See: Box 44, folder 991; Box 45, folder 1002; Box 49, folders 1073d and 1086
      - Wood, Meredith
        See: Box 44, folders 973 and 988
      - Young, Ferry Marquand
        See: Box 44, folder 995
      - Miscellany, 1969-71, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1012a)
  - INTERVIEWS
    - Interview with Carol Brandt
      - Transcription: typescript, corrected, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 1013-19)
      - Notes, 1971 Oct 15 (Box 45, Folder 1020)
      - JPM #1 A+B (1 of 4 audiocassettes), 1970 July 10; 1 (Box 52, Item barcode 39002099360795)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - JPM #2 A+B (2 of 4 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 52, Item barcode 39002099360803)
      - JPM #3 A+B, incomplete (3 of 4 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 52, Item barcode 39002099360811)
      - JPM #4 A+B (4 of 4 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 52, Item barcode 39002099360829)
    - Interview with King Vidor
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1023-27)
      - King Vidor on JPM, undated; 1 (Box 52, Item barcode 39002099360837)
  - THE LATE JOHN MARQUAND
    - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1029-38)
    - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1039-47)
    - Draft A, typescript, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1048-57)
    - Draft B, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1058-66)
    - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1067-72)
    - Advertisements, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 1072a)
    - Publicity, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 1072b)
    - Book reviews, 1972, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1073)
    - Fan mail, 1972 Jan-Apr (Box 48, Folder 1073a)
    - Fan mail, 1972 May-Jul (Box 49, Folder 1073b-e)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Actors appearing in stage and screen adaptations of Marquand's works (Box 49, Folder 1074)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 1156
    - Brandt, Carl and Carol (Box 49, Folder 1075)
    - Fiske, Constance and Gardiner
      See: Oversize, Box 51, folder 1157
    - Hale cousins, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1076)
    - Marquand, Adelaide Hooker (Box 49, Folder 1077)
    - Marquand, Christina Sedgwick (Box 49, Folder 1078)
    - Marquand, John P.
      - Single shots (as a child and young man) (Box 49, Folder 1079)
      - Single shots (in middle and old age) (Box 49, Folder 1080)
      - Group shots, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1081)
    - Marquand, Philip (Box 49, Folder 1082)
    - Marquand houses (Box 49, Folder 1083)
  - BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE
    - Business Correspondence, 1967-72 (Box 49, Folder 1084-88)
- Oversize, 1922-58; 2; (2 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from Series II and III. It is arranged in an order consistent with the original material.
  - BRANDT & BRANDT PAPERS
    - Writings
      - Books
        - Castle Sinister [serialized in Collier's ]: printed version, 1938 Feb-Mar (Box 50, Folder 1089)
        - Do Tell Me, Doctor Johnson [serialized in The Saturday Evening Post ]: printed version, 1928 Jul 14 (Box 50, Folder 1090)
        - Don't Ask Questions [serialized in The Saturday Evening Post ]: printed version, 1939 Sep-Nov (Box 50, Folder 1091)
        - It's Loaded, Mr. Bauer [serialized in Collier's ]: printed version, 1942 Jun-Aug (Box 50, Folder 1092-93)
        - Wickford Point: book reviews, 1935 Mar 24 (Box 50, Folder 1094)
        - Winner Take All [serialized in The Saturday Evening Post ]: printed version, 1934 Jan-Feb (Box 50, Folder 1095)
        - Women and Thomas Harrow: [serialized in Ladies Home Journal ]
          - Printed version, 1958 Jul (Box 50, Folder 1096)
          - Advertisement, 1958 Sep 28 (Box 50, Folder 1097)
      - Shorter Works: Essays and Short Stories
        - "The Artistic Touch," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1927 Feb 19 (Box 50, Folder 1098)
        - "Ask Him," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Jan 23 (Box 50, Folder 1099)
        - "Aye, In the Catalogue," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1928 Aug 11 (Box 50, Folder 1100)
        - "Beginning Now," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1939 Apr 8 (Box 50, Folder 1101)
        - "The Big Guys," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1925 Feb 21 (Box 50, Folder 1102)
        - "The Blame of Youth," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1926 May 29 (Box 50, Folder 1103)
        - "Blockade," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1934 Mar 24 (Box 50, Folder 1104)
        - "Bobby Shaftoe," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1930 Feb 8 (Box 50, Folder 1105)
        - "By the Board," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1923 Mar 17 (Box 50, Folder 1106)
        - "Call Me Joe," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1931 Nov 28 (Box 50, Folder 1107)
        - "The Captain of His Soul," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1922 Nov 4 (Box 50, Folder 1108)
        - "Children's Page," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1940 Aug 31 (Box 50, Folder 1109)
        - "The Darkest Horse," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1929 May 25 (Box 50, Folder 1110)
        - "Davy Jones," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1934 Mar 3 (Box 50, Folder 1111)
        - "Dispatch Box No. 3," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Nov 5 (Box 50, Folder 1112)
        - "Don't You Cry for Me," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1936 Nov 21 (Box 50, Folder 1113)
        - "The Educated Money," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1925 Feb 14 (Box 50, Folder 1114)
        - "Eight Million Bubbles," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1922 Jan 28 (Box 50, Folder 1115)
        - "Everything Is Fine," Collier's: printed version, 1937 Oct 9 (Box 50, Folder 1116)
        - "Far Away," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Aug 13 (Box 50, Folder 1117)
        - "A Flutter in Continentals," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1935 Jun 8 (Box 50, Folder 1118)
        - "The Foot of the Class," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1925 Mar 21 (Box 50, Folder 1119)
        - "Fourth Down," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Nov 19 (Box 50, Folder 1120)
        - "Gentlemen Ride," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1931 Nov 7 (Box 50, Folder 1121)
        - "Golden Lads," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1931 Feb 14 (Box 51, Folder 1122)
        - "Hang It on the Horn," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1936 Mar 21 (Box 51, Folder 1123)
        - "High Tide," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Oct 8 (Box 51, Folder 1124)
        - "How Willie Came Across," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1922 Jul 8 (Box 51, Folder 1125)
        - "Jack Still," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Jun 11 (Box 51, Folder 1126)
        - "The Jervis Furniture," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1924 Apr 26 (Box 51, Folder 1127)
        - "Jine the Cavalry," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Apr 16 (Box 51, Folder 1128)
        - "Just Break the News," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1937 Jul 3 (Box 51, Folder 1129)
        - "The Last of the Hoopwells," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1925 Dec 5 (Box 51, Folder 1130)
        - "The Last of the Tories," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1928 Mar 24 (Box 51, Folder 1131)
        - "Leave Her, Johnny--Leave Her," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1930 Mar 15 (Box 51, Folder 1132)
        - "The Maharajah's Flower," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1937 Mar 27 (Box 51, Folder 1133)
        - "The Marches Always Pay," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1937 Jan 30 (Box 51, Folder 1134)
        - "Mr. Goof," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1929 May 4 (Box 51, Folder 1135)
        - "Much Too Clever," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1925 Apr 25 (Box 51, Folder 1136)
        - "Number One Good Girl," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1933 Oct 14 (Box 51, Folder 1137)
        - "The Old Man," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1925 Jun 6 (Box 51, Folder 1138)
        - "Only a Few of Us Left," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1922 Jan 14, 21 (Box 51, Folder 1139)
        - "The Powaw's Head," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1929 Jul 20 (Box 51, Folder 1140)
        - "Pozzi of Perugia," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1924 Nov (Box 51, Folder 1141)
        - "Pull, Pull Together," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1937 Jul 24 (Box 51, Folder 1142)
        - "The Right That Failed," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1921 Jul 23 (Box 51, Folder 1143)
        - "Sold South," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1932 Mar 12 (Box 51, Folder 1144)
        - "Step Easy, Stranger," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1934 Apr 14 (Box 51, Folder 1145)
        - "The Sunbeam," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1923 Jan 20 (Box 51, Folder 1146)
        - "Take the Man Away," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1934 May 12 (Box 51, Folder 1147)
        - "There Is a Destiny," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1930 Nov 8 (Box 51, Folder 1148)
        - "Time for Us to Go," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1934 Apr 28 (Box 51, Folder 1149)
        - "Tolerance," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1931 Oct 17 (Box 51, Folder 1150)
        - "The Unknown Hero," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1927 Jul 30 (Box 51, Folder 1151)
        - "Upstairs," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1931 Aug 8 (Box 51, Folder 1152)
        - "What's It Get You?," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1935 Jul 13 (Box 51, Folder 1153)
        - "Yankee Notion," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1935 Nov 2 (Box 51, Folder 1154)
        - "You Can't Do That," The Saturday Evening Post: printed version, 1935 Jun 22 (Box 51, Folder 1155)
  - STEPHEN BIRMINGHAM PAPERS
    - Photographs
      - Book-of-the-Month Club meeting: photograph of painting from the mid-1940s by Joseph Hirsch, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1156)
      - Fiske, Constance and Gardiner, with John P. Marquand et al. at Kents Island, Mass., in 1948 [reproduction] (Box 51, Folder 1157)